{
  "1.1": {

      "mcq": [
          {
              "id": 1,
              "type":"mcq",
              "question": "Name the place of pilgrimage where this battle took place.",
              "options": [
                  "Kurukshetra",
                  "Mathura",
                  "Rishikesh",
                  "Varanasi"
              ],
              "correctOption": 0
          },
          {
              "id": 2,
              "type":"mcq",
              "question": "What is the recommended approach for reading Bhagavad-gita, according to the Gita-Mahatmya?",
              "options": [
                  "Skim through the verses quickly to get a general understanding.",
                  "Read it independently and form personal interpretations.",
                  "Read it carefully with the assistance of a devotee of Śrī Kṛṣṇa, avoiding personally motivated interpretations.",
                  "Listen to audio versions without reading the text."
                  
              ],
              "correctOption": 2
          },
          {
            "id": 3,
            "type":"mcq",
            "question": "What establishes the Bhagavad Gita as the perfect theistic science?",
            "options": [
                "It is a compilation of profound philosophical insights presented over centuries by various scholars.",
                "The Bhagavad Gita is authored by Lord Śrī Kṛṣṇa, the Supreme Personality of Godhead, making it a direct discourse from the Divine.",
                "It is widely endorsed by contemporary spiritual leaders for its relevance and wisdom.",
                "The Bhagavad Gita provides an extensive guide to theistic principles and practices, offering a comprehensive understanding of divine science."
            ],
            "correctOption": 1
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "type":"mcq",
          "question": "Why did Dhṛtarāṣṭra express fear regarding the holy place's influence on the battle in the Mahabharata?",
          "options": [
              "He believed the holy place would favorably impact the Pāṇḍavas.",
              "He thought the holy place would be neutral in its influence.",
              "He was confident that the holy place would support his sons.",
              "He was indifferent to the influence of the holy place."
          ],
          "correctOption": 0
         },
         {
          "id": 5,
          "type": "mcq",
          "question": "How was Saïjaya able to envision the Battlefield of Kurukṣetra?",
          "options": [
              "Through his own mystical powers",
              "By practicing deep meditation",
              "By the mercy of Vyāsa, his teacher",
              "Through a divine revelation"
          ],
          "correctOption": 2
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "type": "mcq",
        "question": "What is the significance of the paddy field analogy in the context of the religious field of Kurukṣetra?",
        "options": [
        "To emphasize the abundance of crops in Kurukṣetra",
        "To highlight the need for agricultural development",
        "To symbolize the removal of unwanted elements in the religious field",
        "To promote the cultivation of paddy in Kurukṣetra"
        ],
        "correctOption": 2
        }
      ],
      
      "mtf": [
          {
              "id": 1,
              "type":"mtf",
              "question": "Match the character with their role.",
              "options": [
                { "character": "Arjuna", "role": "Warrior" },
                { "character": "Bhishma", "role": "Grandfather and General" },
                { "character": "Krishna", "role": "Charioteer" },
                { "character": "Duryodhana", "role": "Kaurava Prince" }
              ],
              "correctOrder": [2, 0, 3, 1]
            }
      ]
      
      
  },
  "1.2": {

      "mcq": [
          
        {
            "id": 1,
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "What is the composition of an 'akñauhiṇī' as described in Bhagavad-gītā 1.2?",
            "options": [
            "21,870 chariots, 21,870 elephants, 65,610 cavalry, and 109,350 infantry",
            "10,000 chariots, 30,000 elephants, 50,000 cavalry, and 100,000 infantry",
            "25,000 chariots, 20,000 elephants, 70,000 cavalry, and 120,000 infantry",
            "30,000 chariots, 25,000 elephants, 80,000 cavalry, and 150,000 infantry"
            ],
            "correctOption": 1
            },
          {
              "id": 2,
              "question": "What did Dh\u1e5btar\u0101\u1e63\u1e6dra inquire from Sa\u00f1jaya?",
              "options": [
                  "What did they do in Kurukshetra?",
                  "How many soldiers were there?",
                  "Who will win the war?"
              ],
              "correctOption": 0
          }
      ],
      "mtf": [
          {
              "id": 1,
              "question": "Match the character with their role.",
              "options": [
                { "character": "Arjuna", "role": "Warrior" },
                { "character": "Bhishma", "role": "Grandfather and General" },
                { "character": "Krishna", "role": "Charioteer" },
                { "character": "Duryodhana", "role": "Kaurava Prince" }
              ],
              "correctOrder": [2, 0, 3, 1]
            }
      ]
      
      
  },
  "1.4": {

    "mcq": [
        
        {
            "id": 1,
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Who among the following warriors is fighting on the side of the Pandavas?",
            "options": [
              "Jayadratha",
              "Yuyudhäna",
              "Käçiräja",
              "Droëäcärya"
            ],
            "correctOption": 2
          }
          ,
          {
            "id": 2,
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Identify the warrior aligned with the Kauravas.",
            "options": [
              "Bhuriçravä",
              "Drupada",
              "Karëa",
              "Çaibya"
            ],
            "correctOption": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3,
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Who is not fighting for either the Pandavas or Kauravas?",
            "options": [
              "Kuntibhoja",
              "Sons of Draupadé",
              "Vikarëa",
              "Dhåñöaketu"
            ],
            "correctOption": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 4,
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Which warrior is on the side of the Kauravas?",
            "options": [
              "Cekitäna",
              "Açvatthämä",
              "Uttamaujä",
              "Yudhämanyu"
            ],
            "correctOption": 2
          },
          {
            "id": 5,
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Who is fighting on the side of the Pandavas among the listed warriors?",
            "options": [
              "Kåpa",
              "Bhéñma",
              "Purujit",
              "Çalya"
            ],
            "correctOption": 3
          }
          
          
          
          
    ],
    "mtf": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "Match the character with their role.",
            "options": [
              { "character": "Arjuna", "role": "Warrior" },
              { "character": "Bhishma", "role": "Grandfather and General" },
              { "character": "Krishna", "role": "Charioteer" },
              { "character": "Duryodhana", "role": "Kaurava Prince" }
            ],
            "correctOrder": [2, 0, 3, 1]
          }
    ]
    
    
}
}